datafloq.com 2018-12-27

# Datafloq: Privacy Policy

## **Introduction**

At Datafloq.com ("Datafloq") we appreciate your readership and support and place a high value on your personal privacy. We respect the personal nature of the information you provide us on our website and faithfully recognize the importance of protecting this information. In adopting this privacy policy (this "Privacy Policy"), our intent is to balance our legitimate business interests in collecting and using your personal information with your reasonable expectations of privacy.

Datafloq takes your privacy very seriously and shall handle your personal data with the utmost security and care. In this Privacy Statement, you will learn how we handle your data as well as learn about your rights concerning our processing of your data. We advise that you read this Privacy Statement thoroughly. Should you have any questions or remarks, please contact us at [info@datafloq.com](mailto:info@datafloq.com).

##  **Who is Datafloq?**

Datafloq is the besloten vennootschap Datafloq BV, with registered office at (2596 AL) Den Haag listed at the Traderegister of the Dutch Chamber of Commerce under 61258059.

Datafloq is as the controller ultimately responsible with regard to the processing of your personal data.

Datafloq has appointed a data protection officer. You may contact Mark van Rijmenam at mark[at]datafloq.com.

##  **How does Datafloq use your personal data?**

Underneath you will find an overview of the purposes for the processing of your personal data. You will also find a specification of which data Datafloq uses for that specific purpose, the legal justification, and the amount of time Datafloq keeps this data. For clarity’s sake, we have categorised the purposes.

###  **Services, customer management and financial administration**

Purpose:

| 

 _Financial administration_  
  
---|---  
  
Information:

| 

Company name, Billing address  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legal obligation  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Order Management_  
  
Information:

| 

Home address, Email, Order Number, VAT number  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Handling complaints_  
  
Information:

| 

Home address, Email, Order Number, VAT number  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Invoicing_  
  
Information:

| 

Home address, Email, Order Number, VAT number  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Services_  
  
Information:

| 

Home address, Email, Data necessary to provide the service, Data generated by the service  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Handling complaints_  
  
Information:

| 

Home address, Email, Data necessary to provide the service, Data generated by the service  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Invoicing_  
  
Information:

| 

Home address, Email, Data necessary to provide the service, Data generated by the service  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _CRM_  
  
Information:

| 

Name, Username, Email, Location, Social media account, Browser, OS, User ID, Profile photo  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
importance:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
###  **Marketing**

Purpose:

| 

 _Direct marketing_  
  
---|---  
  
Information:

| 

Name, Home address, Email, Click behaviour, Online behaviour, Social media account, User ID Legitimate interests  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Newsletter_  
  
Information:

| 

Name, Home address, Email, Click behaviour, Online behaviour, Social media account, User ID Legitimate interests  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Retargeting_  
  
Information:

| 

Click behaviour, Online behaviour, Social media account, User ID Legitimate interests  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Social media marketing_  
  
Information:

| 

Name, Click behaviour, Online behaviour, Social media account, User ID Legitimate interests  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Behavioural targeting_  
  
Information:

| 

Click behaviour, Online behaviour, Social media account, User ID Legitimate interests  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
###  **Website**

Purpose:

| 

 _Website analytics_  
  
---|---  
  
Information:

| 

Online behaviour, Location  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _A/B testing_  
  
Information:

| 

Online behaviour, Location  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Account_  
  
Information:

| 

Name, Email, Message content  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Submitting reviews or messages_  
  
Information:

| 

Name, Email, Message content  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
Purpose:

| 

 _Chat feature_  
  
Information:

| 

Name, Email, Message content  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Necessary for the performance of a contract  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
###  **Security and fraud prevention**

Purpose:

| 

 _ID verification_  
  
---|---  
  
Information:

| 

Electronic identification  
  
Legal basis:

| 

Legitimate interests  
  
Interest concerned:

| 

Commercial interests  
  
Storage period:

| 

As long as necessary for this purpose  
  
|   
  
##  **How did we obtain your personal data?**

Datafloq has obtained your data because you have provided this data to us.

##  **What are your rights?**

Under the European General Data Protection Regulation you have a number of rights with regard to your data and the processing thereof:

###  **Access**

You may access your personal information and make any necessary changes in your account. If you would like to see which personal data Datafloq has obtained about you, you may exercise your right of access by submitting a request to Datafloq. In addition, if you have an account on Datafloq, you can also delete any data that we have collected from you. You can also request an archive of all the data that we have collected.

###  **Making changes**

If you wish to make changes to the personal information that you have seen as a result of a request for access and you are unable to make the changes yourself in your account, you may request that Datafloq makes these changes for you. You may request that Datafloq modifies, corrects, supplements, erases or shields your information.

###  **Restriction of processing of personal data**

You also have the right, under certain conditions, to ask Datafloq to restrict the processing of your personal data.

###  **Right to object**

If processing of your data takes place on the grounds of 'legitimate interest' by Datafloq or a third party, you have the right to object to that processing.

###  **Portability of data**

You have the right to obtain your personal data from Datafloq. Datafloq will provide this in a structured and commonly used format, which can easily be opened using commonly used digital systems.

###  **Automated processing**

Whenever a decision about you is taken that is completely based on automated processing of your personal data, you have the right to request that that decision be re-evaluated by a person. You may at all times let us know your position on that decision or let us know that you do not agree with our decision.

###  **Withdrawing** **Consent**

When the legal basis for a particular processing is your explicit consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent. This does not affect past processing, but does mean that we will no longer be allowed to process this data in the future. It may also result in Datafloq no longer being able to provide you with certain services.

##  **Response from Datafloq**

A request can be sent to [info@datafloq.com](mailto:info@datafloq.com). Datafloq will comply with your request as soon as possible and in any case no later than one (1) month after Datafloq has received such a request. If Datafloq rejects your request, we will indicate in our reply why the request was rejected.

##  **Recipients of your personal data**

Your data may be transmitted to:

  * Data processors
  * Parties that are involved in the execution or fulfilment of an agreement between you and Datafloq

It is possible that Datafloq is required to submit your data to a third party, for example, to fulfil a legal obligation.

##  **Transfer to third countries or international organisations**

It may be necessary, for instance for technical and operational reasons, to transfer your (personal) data to affiliates of Datafloq located outside the European Economic Area. Due to the possibility that the regulations in the area of privacy protection do not offer the same protection as within the European Economic Area, Datafloq will use the Privacy Shield or the EU Model Clauses to protect your privacy as much as possible. If that is not possible, Datafloq will ask your consent to transfer your (personal) data to countries that do not maintain an adequate protection level. You may withdraw your consent at any time.

##  **Automated Decision Making**

Datafloq can use automated decision-making processes based on your data when it is necessary for the execution of an agreement between you and Datafloq. It is possible that, based on your profile, you will be shown an adjusted price for Datafloq’s products or services. Datafloq.

##  **What are cookies and how does Datafloq use them?**

Cookies are small pieces of (text) information that are sent to your browser when you visit the website of Datafloq and then stored on the hard disk or in the memory of your device. The cookies placed via Datafloq’s website cannot damage your device or the files stored on it. With 'cookies', we also mean comparable techniques collecting information, such as device fingerprinting.

Some cookies are necessary to operate the website, but these do not collect any personal data. Other cookies we use for statistical purposes, which do not collect any personal data. We also can collect marketing cookies, which do collect personal data. You can determine whether you wish statistical or marketing cookies and at any time you can change your preference via datafloq.com/cookies. Any changes that you make will be reflected automatically.

##  **Can changes be made to this Privacy Statement?**

This Privacy Statement is subject to changes. We, therefore, advise you to regularly read the Privacy Statement for any such changes.

##  **Questions, remarks, and complaints**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the way in which Datafloq uses your data, you can send an e-mail to [info@datafloq.com](mailto:info@datafloq.com). If you have a complaint about the way your data is processed, please send an e-mail to [info@datafloq.com](mailto:info@datafloq.com). Furthermore, you always have the right to contact the competent national data protection authority. In The Netherlands, this is the [Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens](https://www.autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en).

This privacy policy has last been updated on May 25, 2018
